准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
俱乐部
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
准备好  出发了
And there's that and here we go
快看啊  是脏鱼锅
Wey, wook, it's Windward
什么
What?
脏鱼锅要丧班了
Windward's wolling to work
他在哪丧班
Where does he work?
在穴堡黄吗
Wat the Wusty Wab?
那是在说什么鬼话
What's that supposed to be
某种没营养的暗号吗
some kind of stupid secret code?
不能跟你说
We can't tell you
你不是俱乐部的会员
'cause you're not a member of the club
是吗
Oh, yeah?
除了当白痴以外  加入还有什么条件
What does it take to be a member besides being a moron?
当白痴
Moron
是一个条件
as a requirement
抱歉  章鱼哥
Sorry, Squidward
就算你试过了  也不能加入
but you couldn't get in even if you tried
我倒要让你们知道
Well, I'll have you know
我可是加入了全海底20家高级俱乐部
that I am a member of over 20 different
exclusive clubs all across the sea bottom
他说什么
What did he say?
不知道
I don't know
说的是他鼻子吧
Something about his nose
章鱼哥  你跟你鼻子绝对塞不进来
Squidward, you and your nose will definitely not fit in
你们两个废物怎么知道塞不塞得进来
What do you two zeros know about fitting in?
反倒是你们该求我加进来
Why, you should be begging me to join
章鱼哥  不行
Squidward, no
住手
Stop
不不不
No, no, no
住手
Stop
住手  章鱼哥
Stop, Squidward
你不能加入
You can't join
不能加入
Can't join
你不能进来
You can't get in
什么破玩意
Well, this is stupid
里面根本没地方
There's no room up here
我们一直就想提醒你这件事
That's what we've been trying to tell you
我们已经困在这上面三天了
We've been stuck up here for three days
早就提醒过你塞不进来了
We told you you wouldn't fit in
那既然你进来了  章鱼哥
Well, since you're here, Squidward
就给你举行个新会员加入仪式
we'll give you the new member initiation
准备好了吗  派大星
Are you ready, Patrick?
好了
Ready
欢迎加入俱乐部  欢迎加入俱乐部
Welcome to our club, welcome to our club
欢迎章鱼哥  欢迎章鱼哥
Welcome Squidward, welcome, Squidward
Welcome, Squidward, welcome, Squidward
都给我闭上你们的臭嘴
Shut your half-wit pie holes
我现在不想  以后也不想
I do not now nor will I ever
成为你们这破烂俱乐部的会员
want to be a member of your stupid club
许个愿吧  亲爱的
Make a wish, honey
再来
Again
完了
Oh, no
不可能出那回事
This didn't just happen
拜托告诉我没出那回事
Please, tell me that didn't happen
哪回事
What happened?
这是在哪
Where are we?
我们迷路了
We're lost
无路可逃了
There's no way out
困在荒郊野岭
Stuck in the middle of nowhere
还跟海绵宝宝跟派大星一起
with Spongebob and Patrick
为什么我一生每11分钟
Why must every 11 minutes of my life
都会充满不幸
be filled with misery?
为什么
Why?
振作点  章鱼哥
Cheer up, Squid
还会更糟的
It could be worse
对啊  你可能会秃头还长个大鼻子
Yeah, you could be bald and have a big nose
我们玩完了
Well, this is the end
还没有  章鱼哥
No, it's not, Squidward
逝者安息
海绵宝宝    派大星
是吗
It's not?
没关系的
Come on, guys
只要团结一致  我们一定会没事
We're going to be fine as long as we stick together
别忘了  我们是个俱乐部
Remember, we're a club
并且我们有这个
And besides, we have this
什么东西
What's that?
是魔法海螺
The magic conch shell
快问话
Ask it something
魔法海螺  我会结婚吗
Magic conch shell, will I ever get married?
也许将来会
Maybe someday
你们开什么玩笑
You've got to be kidding
这就一破玩具
That is just a stupid toy
怎么可能会帮得上忙
How can that possibly help us?
章鱼哥
Squidward
不可以质疑魔法海螺的智慧
we must never question the wisdom of the magic conch
俱乐部成员都会听从它的建议
The club always takes its advice
然后才做事
before we do anything
海螺无所不知
The shell knows all
魔法海螺
Oh, magic conch shell
怎么办才能走出这片海草林
what do we need to do to get out of the kelp forest?
什么都不做
Nothing
海螺发话了
The shell has spoken
什么都不做
Nothing?
不能光坐着什么都不做啊
We can't just sit here and do nothing
你们居然要
I can't believe you two are going
听从玩具的建议
to take advice from a toy
好了  好了
All right, all right
我不需要你们帮忙
I don't need your help
我会找到重回理智的道路
I am going to find my way back to sanity
你们两位伤心小丑
But don't you two sad clowns
可别等你们马戏团塌了就来找我哭
come crying to me
when your circus tent comes crashing down
伤心小丑
Sad clown
伤心
Sad
小丑
clown
什么声音
What was that?
我都来过这里了
I was already here
我得往哪走
Which way do I go?
我迷路了
I'm lost
完全找不到路
I'm hopelessly lost
再也没法走出去了
I'll never get out of here
我自由了
I'm free
接招吧  海绵宝宝跟派大星
Take that, Spongebob and Patrick
完全离不开这个地方
There's no way out of here
你们神奇智慧海螺俱乐部情况如何
How's it going over there at Club Shell for Brains?
我饿了
I am hungry
不知道章鱼哥俱乐部今晚吃什么
I wonder what's on the menu for Club Squidward tonight
很香吧  海绵宝宝
And that smell good, Spongebob?
你都好几天没吃东西了
You haven't eaten in days
那你呢  派大星
What about you, Patrick?
海星是铁  饭是钢
A big boy's got to eat
不准你们吃
Well, you can't have any
知道什么原因吗  海绵宝宝
And do you know why, Spongebob?
原因就是你们俱乐部主席是个海螺
Because your club president is a shell
要是你们听了我的话
If you had listened to me
就会有食物  避难所
you'd have food, shelter
还有熊熊的篝火
and a roaring fire
然而你们非要听个会说话的蛤蜊
but instead you listened to a talking clam
叫你们什么都不做
that tells you nothing
搞得好像你们一切问题的答案
'Cause the answers to all your problems
会从天上掉下来一样
will fall right out of the sky
从天上掉下来
Fall right out of the sky
我们就快从天上掉下来了
Dude, we're falling right out of the sky
必须卸货减少负重
We got to drop the load
卸货
野餐补给公司
赞美魔法海螺
Praise the magic conch
海绵宝宝  你们那边的吃的还真多啊
Hey, Spongebob, that sure is a lot of food you got there
这是魔法海螺的赠礼
It's a gift from the magic conch
所有东西看着都好好吃
Everything sure looks delicious
烟熏香肠  我最爱了
Smoked sausages, my favorite
海绵宝宝
Hey, Spongebob
你知道我先前都是在开玩笑吧
you know I was just kidding around earlier
我是说  我还是俱乐部的一员吧
I mean, I'm still part of the club, right?
毕竟俱乐部要团结一致
And after all, the club got to stick together
就是说
I mean, you know
章鱼哥
Squidward
怎么了
Yes?
一朝当会员  终生成会员
Once a member, always a member
敬俱乐部
To the club
好
Yeah
抱歉先失陪了
Now, if you'll excuse me
我要先吃什么呢
What shall I eat first
意大利面  火鸡
the spaghetti, the turkey
汤  罐头肉
the soup, the canned meat?
为什么不问问魔法海螺呢  章鱼哥
Why don't you ask the magic conch, Squidward?
搞得好像我真会问一样
Oh, yeah, like that'll happen
还不如先去问魔法脚趾甲
Right after I consult the magic toenail
章鱼哥  你是在质疑
Squidward, are you questioning
魔法海螺的权威吗
the authority of the magic conch?
是海螺向我们恩赐了这场盛宴
The conch is the one who gave us this banquet
这个有版权保护的海螺
This copyrighted conch
是我们俱乐部的基石
is the cornerstone of our organization
可能他不当咱同伙
Maybe he's not a brother
你们都误会了
You guys have it all wrong
我爱这块塑料
I love this piece of plastic
你好啊
Hello, there
魔法海螺  我想知道
Magic conch, I was wondering
我该吃意大利面还是火鸡
should I have the spaghetti or the turkey?
都不能
Neither
那能不能喝汤
Then how about the soup?
不能
I don't think so
我能吃东西吗
Can I have anything to eat?
不能
No
No?
不能几个意思
What do you mean no?
我都饿坏了
I'm starving here
来  我试试
Here, let me try
魔法海螺  章鱼哥可不可以吃这个
Magic conch, could Squidward have some of this
美味好吃超可口的三明治
yummy, delicious, super-terrific sandwich?
不能
No
我可不可以吃这个
Could I have this
美味好吃超可口的三明治
yummy, delicious, super terrific sandwich?
可以
Yes
好耶
All right
抱歉  章鱼哥
Sorry, Squidward
给我
Give me that
我能吃点东西吗
Could I have something to eat?
不能
No
我能吃点东西吗
Could I have something to eat?
不能
No
我能吃点东西吗
Could I have something to eat?
不能
No
除了不能你就不能说别的吗
Can't you say anything else but no?
请再问一遍
Try asking again
我能吃点东西吗
Can I have something to eat?
不能
No
章鱼哥  你没事吧
Squidward, are you all right?
也许应该问海螺他有没有事
Maybe we should ask the shell if he's okay
有人在吗
Hello, anyone there?
有人吗
Hello?
你们需要救援吗
Do you folks need some help?
我得救了
I'm saved
你都不知道我见到你有多高兴
You don't know how happy I am to see you
我都已经困在这好几周了
I've been stranded out here for weeks
身边还有两个呆头
with these two barnacle-heads
跟他们的魔法海螺
and their magic conch shell
魔法海螺
Magic conch shell?
你是说这个吗
You mean like this?
魔法海螺
Magic conch
我们俱乐部的会员
A club member
我的海螺要我来救你们
My conch told me to come save you guys
为魔法海螺欢呼
Hooray for the magic conches
好了魔法海螺  我们应该怎么办
All right, magic conch, what do we do now?
什么都不做
Nothing
魔法海螺万岁
All hail the magic conch
我的漂亮海马
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
啊
Ah
裤头村的春日
springtime in Bikini Bottom
所有海洋生物
All sea creatures
对换季天生敏感
have an innate sense of the seasonal changes
例如海星
Like the starfish
对四处的环境飞快地感知后
A quick survey of his environment
便会发现
and he knows that
春天到了
It's spring
于是海星脱下了冬装
The starfish then sheds his winter coat
妥善保存  以备将来过冬
and stores it away safe for winter
最好打电话找医生
I better call the doctor
因为我得了春天热
'cause I've got spring fever
早安  小花
Good morning, little flowers
早安  章鱼哥
Good morning, Squidward
今天天气真好
Isn't it a lovely day?
你跟小花问好了没
Did you say hello to the flowers yet?
早安  小花
Good morning, flowers
我都不知道章鱼哥对花粉过敏
Gosh, I didn't know Squidward had hay fever
这就帮他
I'll do him a kindness
种点不容易过敏的花
and planet some hypoallergenic flowers
茁壮成长吧
You're on your way
你一定渴了
I bet you're thirsty
我要一直盯着你不放
I'm not taking my eyes off you
三天后
海绵宝宝
Hey, Spongebob
嗨  派大星
Hi, Patrick
怎么老是这样
How does this keep happening?
它好美啊
She's beautiful
好漂亮的海马
What a magnificent sea horse
我要驯服它
I shall tame her
天晓得能达成什么样的成就
Who knows what we can accomplish
由于它行为神秘
"Because of her mysterious behavior
我决定将其取名为神秘
I have decided to name her Mystery"
但既然我想到
Now that I think about it
它还很优雅威严
she's also very graceful and majestic
也许应该要取名优雅或者威严
Perhaps I should name her Grace or Majesty
或者黛比
or Debbie
它一定看到我的花朵书签了
She must have spotted my floral bookmark
它往这边来了
She's coming this way
真乖
That's a girl
别怕
Don't be afraid
我只是个会说话的海绵
I'm just a talking sponge is all
帽子
天啊  神秘
Gosh, Mystery
今天是我一生中最棒的一天了
that was the greatest day of my life
我们会永远当上好朋友吗
Do you think we'll be friends forever?
就当你觉得会
I'll take that as a "yes"
什么
What the?
章鱼哥  还在骑着机器去上班
Hey, Squidward, still riding to work on the machine I see
什么话都别说  章鱼哥
Don't say anything, Squidward
别忘了你的报应
Remember your karma
蟹堡王
吁
Whoa, girl
我上班期间你就在这边等
Now, you wait out here until I'm done with work
下班时候见
See you at the end of my shift
快看  蟹老板装了个摇摇车
Hey, look, Mr. Krabs put in a kiddy ride
要不来玩玩看
Why don't you try it out?
我找不到投币口
I can't find the coin slot
在这边
Here it is
救命
Help
摇摇车发飙了
Kiddie ride on the loose
外面是在闹什么
What's with all the ruckus?
有只怪物
A monster
吓跑了我的客人
scaring away me customers
那不是怪物  蟹老板
That's not a monster, Mr. Krabs
是匹马
It's a horse
它是我的朋友
She's my friend
名叫神秘
Her name is Mystery
你才神秘  海绵宝宝
You're a mystery, Spongebob
除掉它
Get rid of it
拜托蟹老板  让它留下来吧
Please, Mr. Krabs, let her stay
它不会伤着大家的
She won't hurt nobody no how
你跟神秘只能留一个
It's either you or Mystery
早知道就取名黛比好了
I knew I should have named her Debbie
海绵宝宝  谢谢你
Spongebob, thanks
最终还是除掉了那匹马
for finally getting rid of that horse
不用谢  蟹老板
You're welcome, Mr. Krabs
现在能除掉章鱼哥就好了
Now if we could just get rid of Squidward
真好笑  老板
Good one, sir
成功了
It worked, girl
先把你安置在这
I'll just keep you back here
等派大星做完我要的马厩就能出来了
until Patrick finishes
that stable I asked him to build
再八小时就好了
Only eight more hours
十二秒后
不行  神秘
No, Mystery
你还不能出来
You can't come out yet
要是蟹老板看到你的话
If old man Krabs sees you
我会失业的
I'll lose my job
等一下
Wait a sec
你肯定是饿了
I'll bet you're hungry
要不要吃午饭啊
How about some lunch?
嘘  不能吵
Shh, girl, you got to be quiet
不然
or
海绵宝宝  什么声音
Spongebob, what was that?
那匹马在里面吗
Is that horse in here?
没有  蟹老板
No, Mr. Krabs
我只是在模仿神秘
I was just doing my imitation of Mystery
继续努力干活
Well, keep working on it
太糟糕了
That was terrible
太险了
That was close
从现在起不能再闹了
And from now on no more high jinks
上菜了
Order up
海绵宝宝  我的餐呢
Spongebob, where's my order?
托盘底下看了没
Did you look under the tray?
还真没
Oh, no I didn't
抱歉
Sorry
海绵宝宝  能不能好好上菜
Spongebob, could you just get my order?
居然消失了
They vanished
章鱼哥  你觉得蟹堡王是不是闹鬼了
Squidward, do you think the Krusty Krab is haunted?
要是鬼等下来找我怎么办
What if they come for me next?
必须先逃
I got to get out of here
海绵宝宝
Spongebob
世上没有鬼
there's no ghosts
怕你忘了
In case you've forgotten
就告诉你工作流程
here's how things work
我点餐
I order the food
你制作餐点
You cook the food
顾客取餐
Then the customer gets the food
连续干个40年然后死掉
We do that for 40 years and then we die
我感觉很划算
Sounds like a pretty good deal to me
怎么说
What do you say?
明白了  章鱼哥
Yeah, I hear you, Squidward
我马上回来
I'll be right back
什么玩意
What's that?
别跟蟹老板说
Don't tell Mr. Krabs
我都控制好了
I've got it all under control
话说你刚刚有说话吗
Now then, you were saying?
赶紧把餐做好
Just get my order
没问题  章鱼哥
You got it, Squidward
还鬼呢
Ghosts
神秘  你吃了我帽子
Mystery, you ate my hat
神秘  你吃了我锅铲
Mystery, you ate my spatula
肉饼
你把蟹黄堡肉饼都吃了
You ate all the Krabby patties
你吃了炉子
You ate the stove
你吃了老头简金斯
You ate old man Jankins
我不想成为累赘
I don't want to be a burden
我们厨房出了一点小状况
Folks, we have a minor situation going on in the kitchen
我们的餐呢
Where's our food?
我好饿
I'm so hungry
我午餐时间就这一小时
This is my only lunch hour
老头简金斯在哪
Where's old man Jankins?
别着急
Take it easy
反正这边的东西也不好吃
The food's no good here anyway
章鱼哥  怎么回事
Squidward, what's going on in here?
不然就去问问牛仔宝宝
Why don't you go ask Cowbob RanchPants
跟他忠实的伙伴巨能吃好了
and his faithful companion Sir Eats-a-lot
海绵宝宝  那堆外号什么意思
Spongebob, what's the meaning of all these nicknames?
我的戴维琼斯啊
David H. Jones
神秘吃蟹黄堡肚子疼
Mystery got a bellyache from eating Krabby patties
所以我就泡了小苏打给它喝
so I made her a bicarbonate of soda
我错过了什么
What did I miss?
我果然没看错
So, my eyes are correct
我叫你除掉那匹马  结果你却没除掉
You still have that horse
after I ordered you to get rid of it
那现在只能让我亲自彻底除掉了
Well, now, I'm going to get rid of it once and for all
不行  蟹老板
No, Mr. Krabs
求你别让我抛弃神秘
please don't make me give up Mystery
我知道你认为它只是匹马
I know you think she's just a horse
但我跟你说  它不仅仅是匹马
but she's more than that, I tell you
它会听我话
She listens to me
能理解我说的话  我也理解它
She understands everything I say and I understand her
它是我最好的朋友
She's my best friend
谁把这碗洋葱放这了
Who left this bowl of onions here?
海绵宝宝  你的故事感动了我的心
Spongebob, your story has touched me heart
信不信由你
Believe it or not
我知道抛弃好朋友是什么样
I know what's it like to give up a best friend
真的吗
You do?
我五岁那时
I was five years old
我的父亲给了我一块钱
and me father gave me a dollar
我很爱那块钱
I loved that dollar
像爱护兄弟一样爱着它
Loved it like a brother
我和那块钱形影不离
Me and that dollar went everywhere together
那块钱怎么了  蟹老板
What happened to the dollar, Mr. Krabs?
有一天  在海滩上
And one day at the beach
天气很热
it was so hot
我又很渴
and I was so thirsty
我把它花了买汽水
I spent it on a soda
我的好朋友
My best friend
能不能给我拿开
Would you get out of here?
重点在于
The point is, son
虽然很难受  但有时也得学会放手
sometimes you have to set things free
even though it's hard
看看它
Look at her
它想念大自然
She misses the great outdoors
开阔的原野
The wide open spaces
连绵的绿草
the rolling green pastures
厨房并不能成为马儿的家
The kitchen is no place for a live horse
好吧  蟹老板
All right, Mr. Krabs
我能明白
I understand
好了  你可以走了
Okay, girl, you're free to go
我再也不能留住你了
I can't keep you anymore
我知道你很难理解
I know it's hard for you to understand
但蟹老板说得对
but Mr. Krabs is right
你属于大自然
You belong in the wild
你还在等什么
Well, what are you waiting for?
看不出来我再也不要你了吗
Can't you see I don't want you anymore?
快走吧  你这傻动物
Just get out of here, you stupid, dumb animal
它走了
Well, she's gone
我再也看不到它了
and I'll never see her again
没事的
It's okay, son
你做出了正确的事
You did the proper thing
它现在自由了
She's free now
我们无权
and we have no right
把野生动物剥离自然栖息地
to separate that wild animal from its natural habitat
蟹老板
Hey, Mr. Krabs
看样子神秘吃了份餐后沙拉
Looks like ol' Mystery had an after-dinner salad
抓住那匹马
Get that horse
神秘
Mystery
回来
Come back
神秘
Mystery
神秘  快回来
Mystery, come back here
帽子